主演：亨佛莱鲍嘉
英格丽褒曼，保罗韩瑞德
********* 【   北 非 谍 影   】 *********
编剧：茱丽斯艾普斯坦
菲力普艾普斯坦，霍华德柯霍
哈尔华利斯
导演：迈可寇蒂斯
二次大战迫近
很多被困在欧洲的人们
怀着希望甚至急切地
想要来到自由的美洲
里斯本成为热络的航运地点
不过并非每个人均能直接
到达里斯本
因此一条艰苦迂回的
逃难路线出现
从巴黎到马赛
越过地中海到奥朗
然后搭火车、汽车或走路
沿着非洲的海岸线
来到法属摩洛哥的卡萨布兰加
在这里幸运的人
藉着钱、影响力
或运气，可能拿到出境许可证
然后赶往里斯本
再从里斯本到新世界
不过其余的人则在卡萨布兰加
等待、等待、再等待
所有军官注意
两位身怀重要官方文件的
德国快递员
在从奥朗开出的火车上被杀
凶手和可能的共犯
正前往卡萨布兰加
拘留所有嫌疑人物
并搜查被偷走的文件
这个任务相当重要
(法语)
可否看一下你的证件？
我没有带在身上
既然如此
我们必须请你跟我们走
等一下
可能是…
在这里
这些证件三个星期前已过期了
你必须跟我们走
站住！
“自由，平等，同胞爱”
那边发生什么事？
我不知道，亲爱的
对不起，先生，你没听说吗？
我们听到的不多
我们听得明白的更少
两位德国快递员被发现遭谋杀
在沙漠，那无人的沙漠
这是惯例的搜捕自由主义者
难民和给警察首长的漂亮女孩
不幸的是
伴随着这些不快乐的难民
是欧洲的坏蛋们
都集中到卡萨布兰加
有些为了出境证等了好几年
我请求你，先生，自己要当心
谨慎提防
这地方布满贪婪的人
到处都是贪婪的人，到处都是
谢谢，非常感谢
不谢
再见，先生，再见，女士
再见
很有趣的小家伙
服务生
我真笨
什么？亲爱的
我把皮夹子留在饭店
我…
或许明天我们会在飞机上
“瑞克美式咖啡馆”
希特勒万岁！
再见到你真好，史查沙少校
谢谢，谢谢
让我来介绍雷诺队长
卡萨布兰加的警察首长
史查沙少校
未被占据的法国属地
欢迎你来到卡萨布兰加
谢谢，队长，来到这里真好
史查沙少校，这位是我的副官
卡箫副队长
唐里尼队长
意大利军听候指示
下次吧，谢谢
(意大利文)
他听不明白你说什么
(法语)
你可能觉得
卡萨布兰加的天气有一点暖
全德国人必须适应各种天气
从俄国到撒哈拉
或许你所指的不是天气
不然会是什么？亲爱的少校
关于被谋杀的快递员
你们做了些什么？
我们明白到案件的重要性
我的手下逮捕的疑犯人数
是平常的两倍
我们已知道凶手是谁
很好，我已在警方监管中吗？
不必急
今晚他会去瑞克咖啡馆
每个人都会去瑞克咖啡馆
我已听说过这家咖啡馆
并且听说过瑞克他本人
等待、等待、等待
我永远离不开这里了
我会死在卡萨布兰加
可是你不能再加一点吗？
求求你
对不起，女士
可是钻石在市场上不易脱手
所有的人都在卖钻石
到处都是钻石，两千四百元
好吧
卡车准备好了，人手在等着
一切都…
(德语)
是“圣地牙哥号”渔船
明天晚上一点离开
这里，从麦地那号后第三艘船
谢谢，谢谢
并带一万五千元法O现金
记住，一定要现金
不必愁，我们全都预备好了
(俄语)
开门，阿都
是的，教授先生
先生
女士红色
先生黑色
服务生
是的，女士
可否问瑞克要不要跟我们喝酒
女士，他从不跟顾客喝酒的
从来不，我从没见过
是什么原因？
使酒廊老板如此势利
或许如果你告诉他
我在阿姆斯特丹
经营第二大银行
第二大？
那不会叫瑞克刮目相看
阿姆斯特丹的头号银行家
现在是我们厨房的糕饼师傅
我们有值得盼望的事情了
而他爸爸是侍者
给女士的
先生
“一千法O”
“好的，瑞克”
对不起
对不起，先生
这是私人的房间
好大胆，我知道里面在赌博
又不是秘密
你岂敢不让我进去
有什么麻烦？
这位先生
从夏威夷到柏林每个赌场
我都去过
如果你认为
不该让我进这种赌场
你可是大错特错
对不起
哈罗，瑞克
你的现金在酒吧可以用
什么？你知道我是谁吗？
我知道
酒吧让你光顾算你走运
可恶极了
我会向有关当局报告
看你刚才那样对待德国银行家
会以为你整辈子都在做这种事
是什么使你认为我没有？
没什么
不过你刚来卡萨布兰加时我想
你想什么？
我有什么权利去想？
我可以吗？
那两名德国快递员真不幸
对不对
他们走运了
昨天他们还是两名德国办事员
而今天他们成了光荣的死者
你是个很愤世嫉俗的人，瑞克
请原谅我这样说
我原谅你
谢谢，你可否跟我喝一杯
不
我忘了，你从不跟任何人喝酒
请再给我一杯
是，先生
你轻视我，对不对？
如果是我让你这样想
我大概是吧
可是为什么？
你反对我所做的那种生意？
可是为那些可怜的难民想一想
如果我不帮他们必然困死这里
那不算太坏，透过我的方法
我提供他们出境许可证
有代价的，尤佳迪，有代价的
为那些付不起
雷诺开的价钱的可怜虫想想
我以半价替他们弄到手
这算寄生虫吗？
我不反对寄生虫
我反对折价的寄生虫
在今晚之后
所有的事情将成过去
我要离开卡萨布兰加
你的出境许可是向谁买的？
雷诺还是你自己？
我自己觉得自己的价钱较合理
你看
知道这是什么吗？
即使是你也从来没看过的东西
过境信函
由戴高乐将军签名的
不能废止，甚至不能盘问
等一下
今晚我会
以作梦也想不到的价钱卖出去
然后，再见，卡萨布兰加
你知道，瑞克
我在卡萨布兰加有很多朋友
可是不晓得为什么
因为你轻视我
你是我唯一信任的人
请你替我保管好吗？
多久？
或许一小时，或许久一点点
我不要放过夜
别担心，请替我保管
谢谢，我知道我可以信任你
侍者，我正在等一些人
如果有谁找我，我会在这里
是的，先生
瑞克
我想你现在对我比较刮目相看
请恕我失陪，我要跟你的轮盘
分享我的好运气
等一下
我听谣言说那两名德国快递员
身上带着过境信函
我也听过那谣言
可怜虫
你说对了，尤佳迪
我是对你比较刮目相看了
哈罗，瑞克
法拉利
“蓝鹦鹉”的生意如何
很好，不过我想买你的咖啡馆
那是不卖的
你还没听我出价呢！
多少钱也不卖
你要多少才肯卖山姆
我不买卖人口
可惜
人是卡萨布兰加主要商品
光只是难民
我们就能大赚一笔
如果你跟我一起做黑市生意
不妨你做你的，我做我的
我们不妨去问山姆
他喜欢改变一下
我们不妨去问
我亲爱的瑞克
什么时候才明白
在今天这个世界
孤立不再是项实际的政策
法拉利想要你到蓝鹦鹉工作
我喜欢这里
他出双倍我给你的薪水
可是
我在这里赚的钱已没时间花
对不起
老板的私人存货
因为，伊娃，我爱你
闭嘴
好吧，为了你，我会闭嘴
因为，伊娃，我爱你
瑞克先生，瑞克先生
一些德国人付了这张支票
可不可以？
你昨晚到那里了？
那么久以前的事
我记不起来了
我今晚可以见到你吗？
我从不计划那么遥远的事
再给我一杯
沙克，她已喝够了
别听他的，帮我倒满
伊娃我爱你，可是他付我薪水
瑞克，我已厌倦你了
沙克，叫部计程车
是的
来吧，我们去拿你的外衣
别碰我
你该回家，你喝的已够多了
嘿，计程车
你以为你是谁？
把我推来推去
我真是傻瓜爱上你这种男人
你送她沙克，要肯定她回到家
是的，老板
然后马上回来
是，老板
哈罗，瑞克
路易
你真奢侈，这样把女人抛开
有一天她们可能会渐渐消失
我想现在我该去拜访伊娃
或许可藉反作用占到便宜
一讲到女人
你就是不折不扣的民主党
(法语)
如果他听得明白一个字
意大利将大获全胜
往里斯本的飞机
你会想坐在里面
为什么？里斯本有什么好？
到美国的快航
我常思索为什么你不返回美国
你卷走教堂的基金逃吗？
你跟参议员的太太私奔？
我喜欢想像你杀了人
这满足我浪漫的遐想
是三者的综合
到底是什么带你到卡萨布兰加
我的健康，我来卡萨布兰加
是为了这地方的水
水？什么水？我们在沙漠里
我的消息错误
对不起！瑞克先生
里面一位先生赢了两万块法O
出纳需要一些钱
我从保险柜拿
我好难过，瑞克先生
别提了，艾米
这种事常常发生
我非常抱歉
瑞克
今晚这里会有点刺激的事
我们将在你的咖啡馆逮捕人
什么？又一次？
这不是普通的逮捕，是谋杀犯
如果你想要警告他
别让自己不方便
你逃不过监视的
我不为任何人冒险的
明智的外交政策
(法语)
我们本可以在今晚较早时
在蓝鹦鹉进行逮捕
为了表示我对你的敬意
我们在这里进行
可以带给你的顾客一点娱乐
我们的娱乐节目已经够多了
瑞克，今晚我们这里有名贵客
第三帝国的史查沙少校
我们进行逮捕时希望他在场
以示范一下我办事的效率
我明白
史查沙来这里干什么？
他不可能老远来到卡萨布兰加
为了目击你的办事效率吧？
或许不是
拿去吧
不会再发生了
没关系
我知道你心里有事情
何不直接说出来？
你观察力真好
事实上我想劝告你一声
是吗？
要喝白兰地吗？
谢谢
瑞克，在这咖啡馆里
有很多出境证卖出去
不过我们知道你一张也没卖过
所以我们才准许你营业
我还以为是我让你在轮盘赢钱
那是另一个原因
有一个要前往美国的人
已抵达卡萨布兰加
他会给任何提供他出境证的人
一大笔钱
他叫什么名字？
维多拉斯路
维多拉斯路？
瑞克，这是我第一次看到
有人如此令你着迷
半个地球的人都为他着迷
我的责任就是阻止
另一半的地球人不再为他着迷
瑞克，拉斯路绝不能踏足美国
他要留在卡萨布兰加
看他如何达成将很有趣
达成什么？
他的逃亡
我刚才告诉你…
够了，他从集中营逃出来
纳粹党在欧洲到处追捕他
这是追捕的最终站
赌两万法O，不是
维多拉斯路
00:18:45, poor devils who can't meet Renault 's price.
иHb基蠢L抬栓欷 o衡Hネ挛盾H
I get it for them for half. Is that so parasitic?
иぃは癸Hネ挛 иは癸ч基罕Hネ挛
I don't mind a parasite. I object to a cut-rate one.
bさ边ぇ ┮Τ酣票”NΘLh
Well, after tonight I will be through with the whole business.
иn瞒}d履ガ孽d
And I' m leaving, finally, this Casablanca.
A亥X挂\iOV街R骸H p空临OA郅vH
Who did you bribe for your visa? Renault or yourself?
и郅v谋o郅v夯窥耕Xz
Myself. I found myself much more reasonable.
A
Look, Rick.
竟DoOぐ或盾H
Know what this is?
YㄏOA]qㄓS莨L邯F
Something that even you have never seen.
L挂Hㄧ パ拦蔼贾Nx帽W
Letters of transit signed by General de Gaulle.
ぃ嗉oゎA痞埭／嘟L拜
Cannot be rescinded. Not even questioned.
单@U
One moment.
さ边и| H@冠]Qぃ飒夯窥芥Xh
Tonight I' II be selling those for more money than I ever dreamed of.
M帷AAǎAd履ガ孽d
And then, addio, Casablanca.
A竟DA风J иbd履ガ孽dΤ堞hBね iOぃ惧o挨盎
I have many a friend in Casablanca, but somehow, just because you despise me...
]哀A淮跌и AOи斑@Hヴ氦H
...you are the only one I trust.
叫A蠢иO恨n盾H h[H
Will you keep these for me, please?
- ┪\@p伞A- ┪\[@II
- For how long? - Perhaps an hour. Perhaps a little longer.
- иぃn窆L] - O踞み
- I don't want them here overnight. - Don't be afraid of that.
叫蠢иO恨
Please keep them for me.
谅谅Aи竟DиiHHヴA
Thank you. I knew I could trust you.
ㄍ獭Aиタb单@ㄇH
Waiter. I' II be expecting some people.
pGΤ街тиAи|bo
If anybody asks for me, I'll be right here.
O骸Aネ 风J
风J
Rick...
иQA{b癸иゑ耕恁噩郜
...I hope you're more impressed with me now.
叫ぇ讠⒊Aиn蛤A航L だㄉи害nB
If you'll forgive me, I' II share my good luck with your roulette wheel.
单@U
Just a moment.
и钮亮ē弧êㄢWw瓣е患 ōWa帝L挂Hㄧ
I heard a rumor those two German couriers were carrying letters of transit.
и]钮Lê亮ēAi鸡挛
I've heard that rumor too. Poor devils.
A弧癸FAぷㄎ} иO癸Aゑ耕恁噩郜荬F
You're right, Ugarte. I am a little more impressed with you.
- ⒚埂A风J - k┰Q
- Hello, Rick. - Hello, Ferrari.
u屡xMv亥头Np
How's business at the Blue Parrot?
- 堞nAぃLиQRA憨@柏] - êOぃ芥
- Fine, but I' d like to buy your cafe. - It 's not for sale.
- A临S钮иX基OI - hぶ窥]ぃ芥
- You haven't heard my offer. - It 's not for sale at any price.
- Anhぶ~纸妞si - иぃR芥Hf
- What do you want for Sam? - I don't buy or sell human beings.
i堡 HOd履ガ孽dDn坝~
Too bad. That's Casablanca's leading commodity.
uO螟チ и檀N啶j寥@掸 pGA蛤и@_暗堵カネN
In refugees alone we could make a fortune, if you'd work with me in the black market.
ぃЙA暗A骸Aи暗и
Suppose you run your business and let me run mine.
и踏＇h拜si L尺wэ跑@U
Suppose we ask Sam. Maybe he'd like to make a change.
и踏＇h拜
Suppose we do.
и克R悍绉J ぐ或森预~フ bさぱo鹰@ tミぃAO兜龟悔含F郸
When will you realize that in this world today isolationism is no longer a practical policy?
k┰QQnA炻牌xMu@
Sam, Ferrari wants you to work for him at the Blue Parrot.
и尺wo
Oh, I like it fine here.
- LX蛮咖诘恭A毫~ - iO иbo亓泉嚎wS啥―
- He'll double what I pay you. - I ain't got time to spend what I make here.
癸ぃ_
Sorry.
ρ馏酣pHsf
The boss's private stock...
- ]啊Aレ健AиRA - 超L
- ...because, Yvonne, I love you. - Oh, shut up.
naA挨FAAи|超L ]啊Aレ健AиRA
All right, all right. For you, I shut up, because, Yvonne, I love you.
风JネA风Jネ
@ㄇw瓣HIFoiや布 iぃiHH
Some Germans gave this check. Is it all right?
AQ边歙葫丐FH
Where were you last night?
ê或[He酣 иOぃ_ㄓF
That's so long ago, I don't remember.
- иさ边iHǎ歆A盾H - иqぃp购ê或换环酣
- Will I see you tonight? - I never make plans that far ahead.
A倒и@M
Give me another.
- FJAow耻镑F - O钮L骸A腊и撕
- Sascha, she's had enough. - Don't listen to him. Fill it up.
レ涧诜RAAiOLIи~
Yvonne, I love you, but he pays me.
- 风JAиw菇搂AF - FJAs场p{ó O
- Rick, I' m tired of having you... - Sascha, call a cab.
- ㄓaAи胎h厂A亥~ - OIи
- We're gonna get your coat. - Take your hands off me.
A赣^aAA耻氦w镑hF
You're going home. You've had a little too much to drink.
KAp{ó
Hey, taxi.
AH哀AO街H ри崩ㄓ崩h
Who do you think you are, pushing me around?
иuO短ナRWAo贺kH
I was a fool to fall for a man like you.
AeoFJAn蜘wo^飚a
Go with her, Sascha. Be sure she gets home.
O骸Aρ馏 M岚àW^ㄓ
And come right back.
OAρ馏
Yes, boss.
- ⒚埂A风J - 隔
- Hello, Rick. - Hello, Louis.
Au傍ㄗAo妓рkH┻}
How extravagant you are, throwing away women.
Τ@ぱo胎i喾|亥亥ア
Someday they may be scarce.
иQ{bи赣h舫Xレ
I think now I shall pay a call on Yvonne.
┪\i虑は@ノ飓Ky
Maybe get her on the rebound.
@量欷kH ANOぃчぃΙ亥隶D囊
When it comes to women, you're a true democrat.
(ky)
pGL钮oフ@应r NjQNj莉秤
If he gets a word in, it'll be a major Italian victory.
┕酱单华涵妇
The plane to Lisbon.
A|QГb丨
You would like to be on it?
挨盎颉H酱单沪长盎颚nH
Why? What's in Lisbon?
飕瓣骇织
The clipper to America.
и`浏连挨盎颛Aぃ穰^瓣
I've often speculated on why you don't return to America.
A辈ǐ毙绑喊颡靼k盾H A蛤把某氦婴莹pbH
Did you abscond with the church funds? Did you run off with a senator's wife?
и尺wQ钩A炳FH o骸ìи龊┆汗IQ
Llike to think you killed a man. It's the romantic in me.
OT酞汉瞀X
It's a combination of all three.
飑超Oぐ或aA欹d履ガ孽d
And what in heavers name brought you to Casablanca?
и喊繁dAиㄓd履ガ孽d O挨Foaよ氦
My health. I came to Casablanca for the waters.
簟Hぐ或簟Hи苔bFz
The waters? What waters? We're in the desert.
и寒Э~
I was misinformed.
癸ぃ_I风Jネ
Excuse me, Monsieur Rick.
丨堡@欹ネ墓FㄢU遏k
A gentleman inside has won 20,000 francs...
X腔莪n@ㄇ窥
...and the cashier would like some money.
иqOId
I'll get it from the safe.
иn螟LA风Jネ
I'm so upset, Rick. You know l- -
O矗FA悝 o贺ㄆ``oネ
Forget it, Emil. Mistakes like that happen all the time.
иD`╆p
I'm awfully sorry.
风J さ边o胤|ΤI肟E酣 и瘫NbA憨@柏]e筏H
Rick, there will be some excitement here tonight. An arrest in your cafe.
- ぐ或HS@ΩH - oぃO炊q憾e贰A
- Again? - This is no ordinary arrest.
O垦炳デ
A murderer, no less.
pGAQn牡iL O琵郅vぃよK AkぃL菏跌
If you're thinking of warning him, don't put yourself out. He cannot escape.
- иぃ哎籀螭H_I - 醇亥~ユF郸
- I stick my neck out for nobody. - A wise foreign policy.
(ky)
и胎互iHbさ边耕Ν b屡xMi娑e
Could have made the arrest earlier, at the Blue Parrot.
挨F恁堙诠铵A悍qN и苔bo囟i
Out of my regard for you, we're staging it here.
iHa倒A号U趣@IT贾
It will amuse your customers.
и酞寒T贾`ヘwg镑hF
Our entertainment's enough.
风JAさ边и坛o卅肠WQ
We're to have an important guest here tonight.
材T野戟亥vdFぶ
Major Strasser of the Third Reich, no less.
и潭i娑e樊骚票妤Lb初
We want him to be here when we make the arrest.
Hボd@Uи快ㄆ寒牟v
A demonstration of the efficiency of my administration.
иフ vdFㄓo胤Fぐ或H
I see. And what's Strasser doing here?
Lぃi唳鸦法莹欹d履ガ孽d 挨Fヘ阑A嚎歙飘牟vaH
He certainly didn't come here to witness a demonstration of your efficiency.
- ┪\ぃO - 偿ha
- Perhaps not. - Here.
- ぃ|AoネF - S闽Y
- It shall not happen again. - That's all right.
и竟DAみ卅敞票 螭＊奖祷ˉXㄓH
Louis, you got something on your mind. Why don't you spill it.
A[诡Oun
How observant you are.
ㄆ龟WиQUiA@n
As a matter of fact, I wanted to give you a word of advice.
O盾H
Yeah?
- n耻フ孽a盾H - 谅谅
- Have a brandy? - Thank you.
风JAbo@柏] Τ堞hX挂靡芥Xh ぃLи酞竟DA@i]S芥L
There are many exit visas sold in this cafe, but we know that you've never sold one.
┮Hи踏~愠\A犁~
That is the reason we permit you to remain open.
и临H艾Oи琵Ab近L墓窥
I thought it was because llet you win at roulette.
êOt@迎歃]
That is another reason.
Τ@迎ne┕瓣氦H w╄Fd履ガ孽d
There is a man arrived in Casablanca on his way to America.
L|倒ヴ蟠（靴LX挂靡氦H @j掸窥
He will offer a fortune to anyone who'll furnish an exit visa.
- Lsぐ或WrH - 蝴h┰吹隔
- What's his name? - Victor Laszlo.
蝴h┰吹隔H
Victor Laszlo?
风JAoOи材@Ω莰 ΤHp攻OA帝g
Rick, that is the first time I've seen you so impressed.
b应ay氦H常哎L帝g
He's succeeded in impressing half the world.
и撼dヴNOゎ t@b害ayHぃA哎L帝g
It's my duty to see that he doesn't impress the other half.
风JA┰吹隔荡ぃ嘟瘿瓣 Lndbd履ガ孽d
Laszlo must never reach America. He stays in Casablanca.
荪Lp蠊FΘN堞辰
It'll be interesting to see how he manages.
- FΘぐ或H - L喊k`
- Manages what? - His escape.
- и瑜~iDAK - 镑F
- But I just told you... - Stop it.
Lq栋い犁kXㄓ 呛槟姚b稼w斐Bl伐L
He escaped from a concentration camp. The Nazis have chased him all over Europe.
oOl藩撼滩庄
This is the end of the chase.
戒ㄢUkΑAぃO
Twenty thousand francs says it isn't.
oO{u憾堋H
Is that a serious offer?
и杞撙FㄢUAиQ寥^ㄓ
I just paid out 20, and I' d like to get it back.
[欷QUaI иuO映ha夯G毖xO
Make it 10. I'm only a poor corrupt official.
- na - Θユ
- Okay. - Done.
ぃ恨Lho LごM惠n@鳐X挂\i靡 ┪\и赣弧Oㄢ
No matter how clever he is, he still needs an exit visa. Or I should say two.
- 挨盎颥Oㄢ鳌H - L蛤@欷kh@_圈
- Why two? - He is traveling with a lady.
- @鳐L]|n - иぃ{啊Aи莨Lê欷kh
- He'll take one. - I think not. I' ve seen the lady.
pGLSрodb皑辽┪而
And if he did not leave her in Marseilles or Oran...
蜘wぃ|рodbd履ガ孽d
...he certainly won't leave her in Casablanca.
┪\LSΤAê或龊
Maybe he's not quite as romantic as you are.
常@妓ALぃ|敞欹X挂靡
It doesn't matter. There is no exit visa for him.
Oぐ或ㄏA谋oиi唳晨辰 腊Γ┰吹隔k`
What ever gave you the impression that I might help Laszlo escape?
]啊A克R悍绉J иh好bê极@耳U亥~恧U
Because, my dear Ricky, I suspect that under that cynical shell...
A氦氦攥O萤时・いH
...you are at heart a sentimentalist.
An豪HKA ぃLи搓ォ剪晶A喊O魁
Laugh if you will, but I happen to be familiar with your record.
琵и|Xㄢ兜
Let me point out just two items:
b1935~ ABj瘪歃绡沥迁
In 1935, you ran guns to Ethiopia.
b1936~AAb璇Z 蠢は虍原衄％触M
In 1936, you fought in Spain on the Loyalist side.
GΩи常o炻撰p汗S骋
And got well paid for it on both occasions.
秤よセiH倒A螃n汗S骋
The winning side would have paid you much better.
┪\a
Maybe.
GA绊M nр┰吹隔dbo
It seems you're determined to keep Laszlo here.
и^R妯
I have my orders.
иフFAw瓣当K牡诡
I see. Gestapo spank.
克R悍绉J A蔼簸F当K牡诡杭vTOF
My dear Ricky, you overestimate the influence of the Gestapo.
иぃzAL L踏]ぃzAи
I don't interfere with them, and they don't interfere with me.
bd履ガ孽d иx搐郅v憨RB
In Casablanca, I am master of my fate.
vdFぶ炸婴FAx
- I am... - Major Strasser is here, sir.
- ~杌¨ - ア抄
- You were saying? - Excuse me.
d焊 倒vdFぶ粘苔n害欷l a瘠kh酞
Carl, see that Major Strasser gets a good table, close to the ladies.
иwg倒L程n氦F 竟DLOw瓣H はタL@w钡
I have already given him the best, knowing he is German and would take it anyway.
RRae藩 C营f（猸应u矫
Take him quietly. Two guards at every door.
O骸Ax
Yes Sir
- @ち常非称nFAx - ha
- Everything is ready, sir. - Go ahead.
- 边wAネ - 边wA钉
- Good evening, gentlemen. - Good evening, captain.
- n@遏Г盾H- 谅谅
- Wort you join us? - Thank you.
- 芎a┋A{セ┍ - 宦bM辰l骆
- It 's a pleasure to have you here, major. - Champagne and a tin of caviar.
eи崩滤地矗i 堞n邯k瓣s
May I recommend Veuve Clicquot '26, a good French wine.
谅谅 n骸Aネ
Very well, sir.
- 堞辰飒涵鸭殖 - SOOさ边Ax
- A very interesting club. - Especially so tonight, major.
bXだ牧岌AN|莰 ê涌驯Aе患氦H
In a few minutes you'll see the arrest of the man who murdered your couriers.
иタ戳荭p埂A钉
I expected no less, captain.
ぷㄎ}ネ
Monsieur Ugarte.
ぐ或ㄆH
- 叫A蛤и台I - 讽M
- Will you please come with us? - Certainly.
иi_рwX传^{鳌H
May I first please cash my chips?
B黏？O ㄢdA陈沸A ㄢd
Very lucky, huh? Two thousand, please.
谅谅
风JA风JA毕и
Rick! Rick, help me!
- O短FAAkぃ奔 - 风JAри旅_ㄓAQ快k A@wn腊иA风JAQ快k
- Don't be a fool. You can't get away. - But, Rick, hide me. Do something!
风JI风JI
Rick
D`nA钉
Excellent, captain.
讽L台缨歆诋 票妲Ah荷IO
When they come for me, I hope you'll be more of a help.
иぃ哎籀螭H_I
I stick my neck out for nobody.
堠旰pΤI奶睹AU ぃLLhFA@ちキwLㄆ
I'm sorry there was a disturbance, folks, but it's all over now.
鲸恨ГUㄓA荷薄ㄉ nFAsi n骸Aρ馏
Just sit down and have a good time. Enjoy yourselves. All right, Sam.
风J
风JAo飕O材T野戟 μ扒vdFぶ
Rick, this is Major Heinrich Strasser of the Third Reich.
- An盾H风Jネ - An盾H
- How do you do, Mr. Rick? - How do you do?
Awg{醚 材T野戟韩⒋单ネ
You already know Herr Heinze of the Third Reich.
叫@遏ГA风Jネ
Please join us, Mr. Rick.
さ边и太D`a┋
We are very honored tonight.
材T野戟害Wn 场だOvdFぶ摘亥\骋
Major Strasser is one of the reasons the Third Reich enjoys the reputation it has.
L@江狡材T野 n钩Aw品|ΤO氦@妓
You repeat Third Reich as though you expected there to be others.
ぶ铡Ap┏Uи|ㄓ踏）
Well, personally, major, I will take what comes.
AざNи拜A@ㄇ拜D盾H
Do you mind if I ask you a few questions?
- 讽MADタΑ - pGA尺wjiタΑ喊
- Unofficially, of course. - Make it official if you like.
- A喊昴yOぐ或H - иO泳Ks碍
- What is your nationality? - I' m a drunkard.
êㄏ风JΘ哎@嗓渐
And that makes Rick a citizen of the world.
иb矛カXネ pGo癸AΤ腊U
I was born in New York City, if that'll help you any.
и竟DAbぺ兢Q烩 qぺ兢ㄓ斐o
I understand you came here from Paris at the time of the occupation.
êGぃOぐ或当K
There seems to be no secret about that.
AOぃOêㄇ LkQ钩みR氦诰 Qw瓣Hi氦Hㄤいぇ@
Are you one of those people who cannot imagine the Germans in their beloved Paris?
иSΤSO灵薄ぺ兢
It's not particularly my beloved Paris.
A喾Q钩и苔沮鄞岸堋H
Can you imagine us in London?
A歙葫丐Й幡A拜иa
When you get there, ask me.
Τ~ユも得
Diplomatist.
ê矛OH
How about New York?
b矛ΤYㄇ跋办 иぃ|啬厂A沽刚IJ
Well, there are sections of New York, major, that I wouldn't advise you to try to invade.
- A{敖址|ゴ秤MH - и@I]ぃM贰
- Who do you think will win the war? - I haven't the slightest idea.
风J癸@ち常訾ぅ吆A 癸kHよ堡]@妓
Rick is completely neutral about everything. And that takes in the field of women too.
L毛D@建夯颏pみOいミ и苔厂A骇咕憷僧
You were not always so carefully neutral. We have a complete dossier on you.
zd猾扒A瓣HATQC烦 ぃ嗒穰^セ瓣
"Richard Blaine, American. Age: 37. Cannot return to his country."
歃]ΤItk и踏]竟DAbぺ兢暗ぐ或
The reason is a little vague. We also know what you did in Paris.
]竟DA唉舐鞫}ぺ兢CO踞みAи踏７|偿hs冀
And also we know why you left Paris. Don't worry, we're not going to broadcast it.
и翰捶u含O茨舛堋H
Are my eyes really brown?
叫旖抬讵害n_みA猾扒ネAIO
You will forgive my curiosity, Mr. Blaine. The point is...
野戟氦@旒膜H wㄓ欹d履ガ孽d
...an enemy of the Reich has come to Casablanca...
и胎楷d拜ヴ蟑嗬哀诃酞氦H
...and we are checking up on anybody who can be of any help to us.
и癸┰吹隔hdP_嚎辰 潞楝O戒痴好霁Y
My interest in whether Victor Laszlo stays or goes is purely a sporting one.
o妓弧ㄓ A癸lB邯盎┎@ぃP薄
In this case you have no sympathy for the fox?
ぃSOP薄 и]A秆y亥叱
Not particularly. I understand the point of view of the hound too.
蝴h┰吹隔bガ┰妾撼 Zn程L毫括
Laszlo published the foulest lies in the Prague newspapers...
@建歆诃潭iê@ぱ 痞堞bぇ崃佴
...until the day we marched in.
Lb@a耽い ~尿L反l憾浅
And even after that, he continued to print scandal sheets in his cellar.
讽MAぃoぃ┯{Li馥i古
Of course, one must admit he has great courage.
и┯{L芰o bぺ兢LTΩkLи酞捍xみ
I admit he's clever. Three times he slipped through our fingers.
L~尿L含“ и台MNぃ琵o贺ㄆAoネ
In Paris he continued his activities. We intend not to let it happen again.
癸ぃ_Aネ A酞亥头NOFv τи亥头NOg犁s]
Excuse me, gentlemen. Your business is politics, mine is running a saloon.
边wA猾扒ネ
Good evening, Mr. Blaine.
A莰欷FAぶ 风JA@I]ぃゲ踞み
You see, major? You have nothing to worry about Rick.
┪\a
Perhaps.
O骸Aネ
- иqF@应欷lA蝴h┰吹隔 - O骸A┰吹隔ネAo娩ǐ
- I reserved a table. Victor Laszlo. - Yes, Monsieur Laszlo. Right this way.
ㄢMug住vA陈沸A
Two Cointreaux, please.
O骸Aネ
иS莰欷专苇}萎e氦H
I saw no one of Ugarte's description.
蝴h иP谋и踏８盈dbo
Victor, I feel somehow we shouldn't stay here.
pGи滩{bǐXh u|まH`ヘ
If we would walk out so soon it would only call attention to us.
┪\ぷㄎ}b@柏]亥t@娩
Perhaps Ugarte is in some other part of the cafe.
癸ぃ_AA坦超O タne┕瓣氦野
Excuse me, but you look like a couple who are on their way to America.
bê爻oз|Τカ初 иQ⒔姹讥ΑAO碾
You'll find a market there for this ring. I'm forced to sell it at a great sacrifice.
- 谅谅AиSQLRA- ┪\R倒kh
- Thank you, but I hardly think... - Perhaps for the lady.
oзW@LG
The ring is quite unique.
- nAи芊P砍届 - n
- Yes, I' m very interested. - Good.
Asぐ或WrH
What is your name?
ī[A揩陇HA钮援t缓
Berger, Norwegian. At your service, sir.
蝴h
Xだ牧岌讦bsa蛤A|
I'll meet you in a few minutes at the bar.
ぃAиぃQRз 谅谅A倒и态
We don't want the ring, but thanks for showing it to us.
- ê或KyAぃLAMwF - 癸ぃ_AиMwF
- Such a bargain. But that is your decision? - I' m sorry, it is.
- O┰吹隔ネ盾H - O
- Monsieur Laszlo, is it not? - Yes?
иOp空钉A牡诡邯
I am Captain Renault, prefect of police.
OAAQnぐ或H
Yes, what is it you want?
иw铵Aㄓ欹d履ガ孽d 茂Abo卅肀orе
Merely to welcome you to Casablanca and wish you a pleasant stay.
и台盲１`Τo或SX撼X
It isn't often we have so distinguished a visitor.
谅谅Aи票妲A旖抬凇A钉
Thank you. I hope you'll forgive me, captain.
ヘe邯k瓣娆F讽Ы 毛D@建夯颏偷
The present French administration hasn't always been so cordial.
eиざ残レ诧Ypj
May I present Miss llsa Lund.
и钡飚Щ¨AOd履ガ孽d ΤvHㄓ程R氦kX
I was told you were the most beautiful woman ever to visit Casablanca.
êO彩菠SOu夯―k
That was a gross understatement.
Aび犬黏F
You're very kind.
⌒ @_Гa - pGA愠\и
- Wort you join us? - Lf you will permit me.
悝獭A倒и@~程n涵宦b Obи罕bW
Oh, no, Emile, please. A bottle of your best champagne. And put it on my bill.
n骸Aネ 钉
ネAoOи酞豹氦@贺C栏 L贪Obb虫W и脊反b虫D`よK
It's a game we play. They put it on the bill, I tear up the bill. It is very convenient.
钉Au^酣涵婴H
Captain, the boy who's playing the piano...
иn钩bê噩莨L
Somewhere I' ve seen him.
- siH - O
- Sam? - Yes.
L蛤风J@_qぺ兢ㄓ
He came from Paris with Rick.
风JHLO街H
Rick? Who is he?
- khAAタb风J@柏] 风JOK - LOぐ或H
- Mademoiselle, you are in Rick's. Rick is... - Is what?
khALOê贺K pGиOkH焊
Mademoiselle, he's the kind of man that, well, if I were a woman...
и莱赣|RWL酣kH
...and I were not around, I should be in love with Rick.
иuO佣胎 и癸@飕RkH弧O酣kH
But what a fool I am talking to a beautiful woman about another man.
ア抄
Excuse me.
ぶ
Major.
Lpj ┰吹隔ネA琵иざ残 μ扒vdFぶ
Mademoiselle Lund and Monsieur Laszlo, may I present Major Strasser.
An盾H
How do you do?
и弑娉o骱a┋埭[F
This is a pleasure I have looked forward to.
и蜘wA|旖抬冥０骺摔
I'm sure you'll excuse me if I' m not gracious.
ぃLAフAvdFぶ иO倍JH
You see, Major Strasser, I am a Czechoslovakian.
AHe罕锭JH {b AO材T野瓴为vU氦Hチ
You were a Czechoslovakian. Now you are a subject of the German Reich.
иqぃ纯钡o骼u τ{bи甫bk瓣氦gaW
I have never accepted that privilege. And I' m now on French soil.
иQ蛤AQ阶@U Abk瓣gaWま_喊菝D
I should like to discuss some matters arising from your presence on French soil.
啥々MaI常ぃびA讽
This is hardly the time or place.
êи胎tq啥々MaInF ぱQIb邯嚎欷将
Then we shall state another time and place. Tomorrow at 10 in the prefect's office.
n盾Hpj
With mademoiselle.
p空钉AиbA恨烈ぇU
Captain, I am under your authority.
歆A嚎欷将乾OA憨RO盾H
Is it your order that we come to your office?
琵и弧oOи航楔DnF ê妓害r泊ゑ耕n钮
Let us say it is my request. That is a much more pleasant word.
na pj
Very well.
岱|Τ戳
芰o旱Σぉ逝BAぶ
A very clever tactical retreat, major.
- o@ΩL台MNnゎи - 蝴hAи蠢AP飚`┤
- This time they really mean to stop me. - Victor, I' m afraid for you.
и胎He]纯ōBx挂 ぃO盾H
We've been in difficult places before, haven't we?
иゲ斗dXī[竟D酣
I must find out what Berger knows.
- pみI - и|
- Be careful. - I will. Don't worry.
ī[ネ êзиiHA荻堋H iH ネ
Monsieur Berger, the ring. Could I see it again?
叫ㄓ@M宦b蔓Юs
Champagne cocktail, please.
иq厨W悍婴{oA含刍 ┰吹隔ネ
I recognize you from the news photographs, Monsieur Laszlo.
b栋い犁胤QぃG]苊
In a concentration camp, one is apt to lose a little weight.
и态莨LきΩ厨旧AQ炳 bき婴＆P害aよ
We read five times that you were killed in five different places.
C@Ω常Ou龟
As you see, it was true every single time.
谅ぱ谅aAит歆AAī[
Thank heaven I found you, Berger.
иbт@鹰sぷㄎ}氦H LwwOn腊и
I'm looking for a man by the name of Ugarte. He's supposed to help me.
ぷㄎ}郇螟O
Ugarte cannot even help himself.
L]垦炳oQe筏F Lさ边bo爻Q藩
He's under arrest for murder. He was arrested here tonight.
иフF
I see.
ぃLи塘佻O邾绚Ж и胎iH荷O и苔巢章础Aネ
But we who are still free will do all we can. We are organized.
baUAN钩ㄤLaよ@妓
Underground, like everywhere else.
ぱ边WΤ@臃|某
Tomorrow night there is a meeting at the Caverne du Bois.
pGA|ㄓK ネ
If you will come...
i_叫u葵^汗Lㄓ@UH
Will you ask the piano player to come over here?
n骸Apj
Very well, mademoiselle.
- ]_ネNp蟆Hī[ - ぃびnA叫蠢и挡b
- How's the jewelry business, Berger? - Not so good. Check, please.
ui堡AぃΝIㄓo さぱ边Wи苔长@I肟EO?癸ぃ癸Hī[
Too bad you werert here earlier. We had quite a bit of excitement, didn't we, Berger?
癸Aア抄
Yes. Excuse me, gentlemen.
- и罕b虫 - ぃノ ㄢM宦b蔓ЮsA舭U OAネ
- My bill. - No. Two champagne cocktails. Please.
- ⒚埂Asi - ⒚埂Apj
- Hello, Sam. - Hello, Miss llsa.
иqSQL|A莰歆A
I never expected to see you again.
wg埭[F
It's been a long time.
O骸Apj Lh酣痞肠pu
Yes, ma'am. Alot of water under the bridge.
- ㄓ@ㄇ侣ら汉qAsi - OApj
- Some of the old songs, Sam. - Yes, ma'am.
风Jbê亍H
Where is Rick?
иぃ竟DAи俱边S莰欹L
I don't know. I ain't seen him all night.
- Lぐ或森驭^ㄓH- さ边ぃ|ALぃ|^ㄓ
- When will he be back? - Not tonight no more. He ain't coming...
L^aF
He went home.
- L``o或ΝNǐ盾H - Lqぃ
- Does he always leave so early? - He never...
LΤ欷kねb屡xM
Well, he's got a girl up to the Blue Parrot.
L``Wêㄠ
Goes up there all the time.
AHeゑ耕|蓟晾Asi
You used to be a much better liar, Sam.
OhゴZLAレ诧pj A哎LaㄓcB
Leave him alone, Miss llsa. You're bad luck to him.
u@ΩAsiA荭b┕ら鳏W
Play it once, Sam. For old times' sake.
иぃ竟DAOぐ或N洹H レ诧pj
I don't know what you mean, Miss llsa.
uaAsi
Play it, Sam.
uu丧赋uv
Play "As Time Goes By."
иOぃ_ㄓFAレ诧pj иΤIネ驻F
I can't remember it, Miss llsa. I'm a little rusty on it.
и蠢A蠼栅l
I'll hum it for you.
佰XㄓAsi
Sing it, Sam.
si иQиiDLAッ环Ou
Sam, I thought I told you never to play...
A瑜~拜の风JALㄓF LpjA琵иㄓざ残
Well, you were asking about Rick, and here he is. May I present...
- ⒚埂Aレ诧 - ⒚埂A风J
- Hello, llsa. - Hello, Rick.
Awg{醚风JFApj êA┪\A]K
Oh, you've already met Rick, mademoiselle? Then perhaps you also...
o飕O┰吹隔ネ
This is Mr. Laszlo.
- An盾H - An
- How do you do? - How do you do?
bd履ガ孽d钮飓堞hA酣
One hears a great deal about Rick in Casablanca.
τ蝴h┰吹隔酣屁斐BiD
And about Victor Laszlo everywhere.
- 蛤и坛埭@Mn盾H - ぃA风JqぃK
- Wort you join us for a drink? - Rick never...
- 谅谅A- и|
- Thanks, I will. - Well...
@兜Dㄒゴ}FA悝獭I
...a precedent is being broken. Emile.
- oO堙Oo憨@柏] иコ擐A - иコ擐A
- Interesting cafe. I congratulate you. - I congratulate you.
- 挨Fぐ或H - A氦u@
- What for? - Your work.
谅谅Aи荷Oτ
Thank you. I try.
Ha常荷Oτ啊AτAΘ\F
We all try. You succeed.
иぃびフA台猸 oΝb拜闽螫A酣 ê贺A专惜讷D`耳И
She was asking about you earlier, Rick, in a way that made me extremely jealous.
иぃ蜘wOA
I wasrt sure you were the same.
- иQQ и坛太幛@Ωǎ爆O - uR罕岱wv
- Let's see, the last time we met... - Was La Belle Aurore.
びnFAAOo
How nice. You remembered.
ぃLêぱタnOw瓣x钉 }iぺ兢氦椁l
But, of course, that was the day the Germans marched into Paris.
ぃe雩寻O氦椁l ぃe
Not an easy day to forget.
иOoC@硬痈` w瓣H铴铅狻AA锫纽
I remember every detail. The Germans wore gray, you wore blue.
癸Aирêン绐AΜ_ㄓF
Yes. I put that dress away.
讽w瓣HM瞒帷Aи|A
When the Germans march out I'll wear it again.
风JAA跑o耕H┦てF иqи胎捕贩P谅AApj
Ricky, you're becoming quite human. I suppose we have to thank you for that.
レ诧AиぃQ苯砍 ぃL森预＆F
Ilsa, I don't wish to be the one to say it, but it's late.
航TOAbd履ガ孽dΤзY
So it is. We have a curfew in Casablanca. It would never do for the chief of police...
牡诡邯iぃ喑Qo{ 耻Ks醇ぃM
...to be found drinking after hours.
- и票妲AぃざN - @I]ぃ
- I hope we didn't overstay our welcome. - Not at all.
- A罕b虫Aネ - 琵иI  и叫
- Your check, sir. - It 's my party.
S@雍Dㄒゴ}F oO@荧堞辰飒罕撙W
Another precedent gone. This has been a very interesting evening.
и蠢Asp{ó b边WTont倒
I'll call you a cab. Gasoline rationing, time of night.
- и谭|Aㄓ - H膳w
- We'll come again. - Anytime.
- 蠢и蛤si弧边w - и|
- Say good night to Sam for me. - I will.
@嗓WSΤH喙长siê妓 uu丧赋uv
There's still nobody in the world who can play "As Time Goes By" like Sam.
LΤn[Suo汉qF
He hasn't played it in a long time.
- 边w - 边w
- Good night. - Good night.
边w
Night.
o臃绉JsH馋WㄤМ LOぐ或HH
A very puzzling fellow, this Rick. What sort is he?
и]弧ぃWㄓ 瘤Mbぺ兢и`莰欹L
I really can't say, though I saw him quite often in Paris.
- ぱQIb邯嚎欷将 - и谭|h
- Tomorrow at 10, at the prefect office. - We'll be there.
- 边w - 边w
- Good night. - Good night.
ρ馏
Boss?
- ρ馏 - O
- Boss? - Yeah?
- AnぃnW珊巍H - {bぃn
- Boss, ain't you going to bed? - Not right now.
A|bu啥・氦W珊味堋H
Ain't you planning on going to bed in the near future?
ぃ
No
- 边@IA|W珊味堋H - ぃ
- You ever going to bed? - No.
и]ぃx
Well, I ain't sleepy, either.
nAㄓ耻@Ma
Good, then have a drink.
- ぃAиぃnAρ馏 - êNO耻
- Not me, boss. - Then don't have a drink.
ρ馏Aи搪鞫}o丕a
Boss, let's get out of here.
ぃAsiAиb单@欷kh
No, sir. I' m waiting for a lady.
舭UAи台a o匕￥F陈沸ぇ~ぐ或]SΤ
Please, let's go. Ain't nothing but trouble for you here.
o^ㄓFAи竟Do^ㄓF
She's coming back. I know she's coming back.
и潭}óhA}@俱颖撙W
We'll take the car and drive all night.
и胎h耻sぃKぃk и踏]ih敞辰A跟}@U 建歃o瞒}K
We'll get drunk. We'll go fishing, stay away until she's gone.
- 超LA^ahn盾H - ぃAネAиndbo
- Shut up and go home, will you? - No, sir, I' m staying right here.
L抬欷Fぷㄎ} M幡oǐiㄓ
They grab Ugarte, then she walks in.
鄣MkhA@i@X
That's the way it goes. One in, one out.
- si - O骸Aρ馏
- Sam. - Yes, boss?
bd履ガ孽d {bO@E|@~QGるAb矛Oぐ或森浴H
If it's December 1941 in Casablanca, what time is it in New York?
ぐ或H
What?
и氦饪霭堡F
My watch stopped.
иゴ戒b矛L坛：蔚郅F
I bet they're asleep in New York.
иゴ戒瓣氦H常何帝F
I bet they're asleep all over America.
@搔敞夯颚h奥 Τê或hsa
Of all the gin joints in all the towns in all the world...
oNǐiиo@a
...she walks into mine.
- Abuぐ或H - uOиHK睹u
- What's that you're playing? - A little something of my own.
- 氨AA竟DиQ钮ぐ或 - ぃAиぃ竟D
- Well, stop it. You know what I want to hear. - No, I don't.
A喱唉ouAA]喱哀诩u
You played it for her. You can play it for me.
- иQиOぃ_ㄓ - pGooFAи]iH
- I don't think I can remember... - If she can stand it, I can.
uI
Play it.
O骸Aρ馏
Yes, boss.
A飑超Oぐ或HHAHeOぐ或H
Who are you really? And what were you before?
AO暗ぐ或骸H ASQㄇぐ或H
What did you do, and what did you think?
и袒」Lぃ惆莅菝D
We said no questions.
ッxぃа
Here's looking at you, kid.
@kΧRA氦擗
A franc for your thoughts.
b瓣L胎uX@だ窥
In America they'd bring only a penny.
иqj阀u瘸o或h
I guess that's about all they're won'th.
и@NQWBΜO iDи
I'm willing to be overcharged. Tell me.
иbQK
Well, I was wondering...
ぐ或H 挨盎颛讪夯颟BH 挨盎颛A|bê氐サ郄讠X{ タォSQит
Why I' m so lucky. Why I should find you waiting for me to come along.
挨盎颛讵亥桐Rい SΤO酣kHH
Why there is no other man in my life?
ê苈渤妗AHeΤ
That's easy. There was.
L氦F
He's dead.
癸ぃ_и拜F
I'm sorry for asking.
иаFи袒」Lぃ惆莅菝D
I forgot we said no questions.
uΤ@拥 喔训и泰姚唱喊菝D
Only one answer can take care of all our questions.
uぺ兢v
o噩Ow瓣HvS
k瓣HAぺ兢H
k瓣x钉w癖螗L酞罕^
w瓣HwnDiJ撼
Nothing can stop them now. Wednesday, Thursday at the latest, they'll be in Paris.
zdApGL痰o{A汗Lh Adbo孬KぃwF
Richard, they'll find out your record. You won't be safe here.
иΝwbL酞憾娄W虫WF aA逆W
I'm on their blacklist already. Their roll of honor.
毵Qnи坛堙钩o@~
Henri wants us to finish this bottle and then three more.
临ΤT~Lnノㄓ煎 ]ぃ琵w瓣H耻
Says he'll water his garden with champagne before he'll let the Germans drink it.
oiH搭淮Q烩涵Wo A弧OぃOHzdネ
This sort of takes the sting out of being occupied, doesn't it?
A弧癸F
You said it.
ッxぃа
Here's looking at you, kid.
(wy)
и杭wyΤIネ驻F
My Germars a little rusty.
O当K牡诡
It's the Gestapo.
L袒」wpぱ欷诰
They say they expect to be in Paris tomorrow.
L苔b毙и谭恁L潭iㄓ 赣p螭侠
They're telling us how to act when they come marching in.
俱鹰@骚汁摔UㄓF и太oDWo森渊咏团史R
With the whole world crumbling, we pick this time to fall in love.
癸Auぃォ
It's pretty bad timing.
- bQ~e焊堋AA|弧ぐ或H - Q~eH
- Where were you, say, 10 years ago? - 10 years ago?
иQQ
Let's see.
и临a帝M ê森鸳AbêㄠH
Yes, I was having a brace put on my teeth. Where were you?
タbтu@
Looking for a job.
êO钉醵堋H
Was that cannon fire?
临Oи氦擀b铬H
Or is it my heart pounding?
êOs杭w瓣77 虫Hn胆缨P_ juΤTQき环
It's the new German 77th, and judging by the sound, only about 35 miles away.
VㄓV瘠F
And getting closer every minute.
ㄓAㄓA耻
Here, here, drink up.
t~êT~и坛埭＇工F
We'll never finish the other three.
w瓣H堙执N|欷F L谭|ㄓтA
Them Germans will be here pretty soon, and they'll come looking for you.
OаF长UAΤa洁
And don't forget, there's a price on your head.
иbそJdΤr兵 L酞竟D歙葫丿唰洙歆
Ileft a note in my apartment. They'll know where to find me.
_┣A
It's strange.
- и癸AA秆oê或ぶA- и癸A毫A秆螭
- I know so very little about you. - I know very little about you.
u竟DABタL睛
Just the fact that you had your teeth straightened.
ぺ兢
Be serious, darling. You are in danger. You must leave Paris.
ぃAぃAи踏@wn瞒}
No, we must leave.
癸A讽MOи
Yes, of course. We.
┕皑辽氦酲きI}X и|Ib歆A憾憨北掸A
The train for Marseilles leaves at 5:00. I'll pick you up at your hotel at 4:30.
ぃAぃnbи逗┍AиK
Not at my hotel. I...
bи瞒}eиb谤卅敞骗n快
I have things to do in the city before I leave.
и|b酲父颛AI
I'll meet you at the station.
naA|I|Qきだ
All right, at a quarter to 5.
и苔螭＆b皑辽挡B
Why don't we get married in Marseilles?
{bp购ぃ尔び换环盾H
That's too far ahead to plan.
癸AиqO环FI
Yes. I guess it is too far ahead.
ê酲W害Cóp LiHb酲W 蠢и胎DB搂
Let's see... What about the engineer? Why can't he marry us on the train?
克R 挨盎颏！H 差W翰瞠iH GΤIぃそキK
Why not? The captain on a ship can. It doesn't seem fair that...
缁颏FH膜l
Hey, what's wrong, kid?
иê或RA
Llove you so much.
τиê或h氤o驹
And I hate this war so much.
oO雍屁g亥@ ヴ蟥瞥％i嗟oネ
It's a crazy world. Anything can happen.
U@pGAぃ嗦鞫}
If you shouldn't get away...
иO弧AU@и坛Qだ}
If something should keep us apart...
ぃ恨L抬猝Awmbê
...wherever they put you...
ぃ恨и|bê иnA竟DиK
...and wherever I' II be, I want you to know that I...
kи
Kiss me.
Τp程幛@Ω毵kи
Kiss me as if it were the last time.
WóIWóI
`NIWóI
┮Τ极趣Wó 程幛@Z酲bTだ牧岫}X
еIAWóI程幛@Z酲I
obê亍HAΤ莰歃o盾H
Where is she? Have you seen her?
ぃAzdネAитぃ歃o owghF┬丁
I can't find her. She checked out of the hotel.
ぃLA杪鞫}岚eㄓor兵
But this note came just after you left.
u克R翰zdv
uиぃ喔颛Aǐ┪OAǎAv
uAぃn拜挨盎颉v
uun郢HиRAv
u倒и悍RH@W爷褐Av
uレ诧v
êO程岐亥l酬Azdネ
That's the last call, Mr. Richard.
A钮歆诨《堋H
Do you hear me?
еIAи搪鞫}o卅A弧 еIAzdネAеI
Come on, Mr. Richard. Let's get out of here. Come on.
风JAиゲ斗蛤A酵@U
Rick, I have to talk to you.
ир材@MdUㄓ蛤A@_耻 boㄠ
I saved my first drink to have with you. Here.
- ぃAぃA风JAさ边ぃ-  SOOさ边
- No, Rick. Not tonight. - Especially tonight.
挨盎颛A@wnㄓd履ガ孽d 临Τ堞hO害aよ
Why did you have to come to Casablanca? There are other places.
pGи竟DAbo иNぃ|ㄓ
I wouldn't have come if I' d known you were here.
郢HиAêOu и盲＊竟D
Believe me, Rick, it's true. I didn't know.
_┣含OA毫n @I常S跑 иごM钮o
It's funny about your voice, how it hasn't changed. I can still hear it.
克R翰zd и|HA欷巡Pà
"Richard, dear, I'll go with you anyplace.
- и踏@_ГW酲 @隔ぃ氨 - Oo妓A风J
- We'll get on a train and never stop." - Don't, Rick.
иフA悍P
I can understand how you feel.
Aフи悍P
You understand how I feel.
и态郾元氦椁lΤhH 克R
How long was it we had, honey?
- иSΤ计 - иΤ
- I didn't count the days. - Well, I did.
C@ぱ常Τ
Every one of them.
程幛@ぱиOo程M贰
Mostly I remember the last one.
讽T裁nTL るxWΤ@婴H甫bBい
The wild finish. A guy standing on a station platform in the rain...
yW本帝i邯邯肀
...with a comical look on his face...
]哎L氦氦叱Q金陆F
...because his insides have been kicked out.
风J иi_弧@蝇Gㄆ倒A钮H
Can I tell you a story, Rick?
挡Ы]ΤT裁n盾H
Does it got a wild finish?
и临ぃ竟D挡Ы
I don't know the finish yet.
êN弧Xㄓ ┪\@娩弧iH@娩Q
Go on, tell it. Maybe one'll come to you as you go along.
OΤ闽@欷k o璞q齑稻|ㄓ欷诰
It's about a girl who had just come to Paris from her home in Oslo.
b@营Bね寒a
At the house of some friends...
oJ歃o钮DF@晋l酣kH
...she met a man about whom she'd heard her whole life.
@影钉jSi幢酣kH
A very great and courageous man.
L唉o处}@鹰血久
He opened up for her a whole beautiful world...
浞QMzQ舱Θ含R@
...full of knowledge and thoughts and ideals.
o竟D氦@ちAo害í 常Oパ螗L好霁Y
Everything she knew or ever became was because of him.
o春ヵLA
And she looked up to him...
R籁L
...and worshiped him...
o安wêNOR悍P谋
...with a feeling she supposed was love.
癸A墁
Yes, that's very pretty.
и]钮L@蝇Gㄆ ㄆ龟Wbи害~N ]钮L堞hGㄆ
I heard a story once. In fact, I've heard a lot of stories in my time.
常パ灿p嚎^mmn瘾
They went along with the sound of a tinny piano...
Nb加U氦jUu
...playing in the parlor downstairs.
ネAиp森驭长@Ω JW@莹kHA}l`Oo妓
"Mister, I met a man once when I was a kid," they'd always begin.
иqи酞含Gㄆ常ぃ缁颚辰
I guess neither one of our stories is very funny.
iDи
Tell me...
AO挨F街瞒}иH
...who was it you left me for?
O┰吹隔 临Oい丁临ΤO氦H
Was it Laszlo, or were there others in between...
┪抬AOぃ|弧Xㄓ氦H
...or aren't you the kind that tells?
(p空钉A牡诡邯)
и伐狠h好ぷㄎ}ネ рL挂HㄧdU倒猾扒ネF
I strongly suspect that Ugarte left the letters of transit with Mr. Blaine.
и啬偿擗韫┏jd@柏]
I would suggest you search the cafe immediately.
pGHㄧb风JもW Lê或oAぃi唰洙飒
If Rick has the letters, he's too smart to let you find them there.
Aび肛贱L毫o
You give him credit for too much cleverness.
и害LHLぃLOt@ 蝉疾含瓣H
My impression was he's just another blundering American.
AぃnC衄瓣H翰跫
We mustrt underestimate American blundering.
1918~ 讽L滩跫捕iJfL
I was with them when they blundered into Berlin in 1918.
и蛤L苔b@_O 堠螬源蹈 иn￥H24p珊实
As to Laszlo, we want him watched 24 hours a day.
Ai喾|P砍届Q竟D 龚瑗Lタbㄓo鬲撼~い
It may interest you to know that at this very moment he's on his way here.
и台S快k
There is nothing we can do.
馨砍莰歆A獭AA苔偿RだヰФ H
I'm delighted to see you. Did you have a good night's rest?
и何o堞n
I slept very well.
_┣Abd履ガ孽d ぃ莱赣ΤH|何on
Strange. Nobody's supposed to sleep well in Casablanca.
- и胎i_i妤卡啤H - D`贾NA叫ГU 谅谅
- May we proceed with the business? - With pleasure. Wort you sit down?
naAи泰Zフ弧nF AO材T野戟喊kデ
Laszlo, we will not mince words. You're an escaped prisoner of the Reich.
欹孬e挨瞌AΘ\跟Lи
So far you have been fortunate in eluding us.
A╄FFd履ガ孽d
You have reached Casablanca.
иΤdヴTO Adbd履ガ孽d
It is my duty to see that you stay in Casablanca.